本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流之用 更多中日双语字幕，请登录 www.kamigami.org  台本：卷 　翻译:mam  校对: maize　时间轴：花开  后期：娜夏
僕は ネットワーク上に存在する 永遠の命を持った
This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
I'm someone who has gained eternal life on the network.
一つの人格さ
君島コウ…
本来であれば 完璧な形で 移植するはずだったのだが
Kimijima Kou...!
電磁波照射 実験中
By all rights, it should have been a perfect transplant,
瀬乃宮みさ希に殺されるという アクシデントに見舞われてね
but there was an accident during my EM radiation exposure experiment
and Senomiya Misaki ended up killing me.
知らなかったろ
君たちは そのおかげで 命を落とさずに済んだというのに
You didn't know?
Stream preparations ready
どういうこと
It's because of her meddling that you two are alive right now.
あねもね号…
What do you mean?
そうだ 電磁波照射実験
The SS Anemone!
あねもね号の乗客は そのときの実験台だったんだよ
That's right.
An EM irradiation experiment.
しかし 運悪く 瀬乃宮みさ希に 気付かれてしまってね
The passengers aboard the SS Anemone were mere test subjects to me.
Unfortunately, Senomiya Misaki became aware of that.
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Will draw the blood of covenant
真理のために今ここにいるよ
Everything scatters, leaving void
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
The stage with our careless justice
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
Does she still love robots?
Furugoori?
古郡…？
Watch this nao!
From: Furugoori
Subject: (No Subject)
Well, that's a pretty annoying story at any rate.
まったく 迷惑な話だよ
My head smashed just like a watermelon too.
それで 僕の頭は スイカを落としたように粉々になってしまった
これは…
This...
My sister is...
お姉ちゃんが…
だから 僕は１カ月くらいした後に みさ希の所に現れてあげたんだ
So then I manifested myself before her after about a month.
I constantly played on her guilt,
threatening to expose what she did.
彼女の罪の意識をえぐり
僕の力を使えば 罪を白日の下に さらすことなど 簡単だと脅した
思ったより強情だったけどね
She was more obstinate than I expected.
でも 僕は 永遠に まとわり続ける
But I could be around for eternity.
みさ希の大事なものを 傷つけることも すぐにできる
Then I demonstrated my capability of harming what was precious to Misaki.
That threat finally broke her.
そう脅したら 屈したよ
It's a similar situation with this child.
この子と同じようにね
Project Atum was originally scheduled for 2015.
本来 プロジェクト·アトゥムは ２０１５年に 実行する予定だったんだ
It'd be such a waste to stop now.
ここで やめたら もったいないだろ？
Senomiya Misaki sacrificed her whole life for this project!
瀬乃宮みさ希が 自分の人生を 全て捨てて懸けたプロジェクトなのに…
Kimijima!
君島さん
Aki?
アキちゃん…
Younger Senomiya!
瀬乃宮妹
My sister...
うちのお姉ちゃんは 今でも ロボットのことが好きですか？
Does she still love robots?
What?
な…何を… ？
Does she still love robots?
今でも ロボットが好きですか？
Who knows?
さあね？ でも みさ希は ゲームだけは続けていたよ
She sure didn't stop playing games.
That Kill-Ballad or whatever it's called.
『キルバラ』というゲームをね
I'm glad.
よかった
Are you satisfied now?
それで満足なのかい？
Yeah. Robots were our bond.
ええ だって うちにとって ロボットは絆で
ロボットは希望で 仲間との努力の結晶で…
Robots were our hope... the essence of all our efforts.
Robots can't even walk if you don't watch over them.
ロボットは きちんと指示してあげないと 歩くことさえ できなくて
They're hopeless and cause so much trouble.
世話ばっかり焼かせる どうしようもない子たちで…
But if we treat them nicely, they are there for us.
でも しっかり向き合えば 応えてくれて…
GunPro-1, GunPro-2, and
Tanegashimachine-3S are like my children.
ガンつく１も ガンつく２も タネガシマシン３改だって
うちには子供みたいなもの 大好きなロボット…
They are my beloved robots.
And my sister broke them.
それを お姉ちゃんは壊したの
I wonder how it felt for her.
どんな気分だったかな？ つらかったかな…
It must've been hard.
それとも 何も感じることも できなかったのかな…
Or did she not feel anything?
So... So...
だから…だから…
Aki...
アキちゃん…
So...
だから…うちは お姉ちゃんに そんなことをさせたあなたを許さない
I'll make you pay for what you did to my sister!
君島コウ あなたを許さない
I'll make you pay, Kimijima Kou!
Very good. Give it a try.
結構 やってもらおうじゃないか
If you survive now, that is.
生き延びることができたらね
アキちゃん
Aki!
The robots of evil are defeated by robots of justice.
悪のロボットを倒すのは 正義のロボットだって昔から決まってる
It's always been like that!
知らないかもしれないから 君島さんに教えてあげる
I guess Kimijima doesn't know, so let's tell him.
Giant humanoid robots have saved the world dozens, even hundreds of times already!
巨大二足歩行ロボットは
これまでに 何十回も何百回も 世界を救ってきてるんだ
Robots will save the world again!
だから 今回も ロボットが世界を救う
The robot we built! The robot we put all our dreams into!
うちらの造ったロボが
うちらの夢が詰まったロボが
It will defeat your bad robot! It will defeat you!
あなたたちの 悪いロボットを倒して
あなたを倒して
It will defeat my sister!
お姉ちゃんを倒して
It will save the world!
世界を救ってやるんだ
Damn the Committee of 300, Project Atum, and Kimijima Kou!
三百人委員会も
プロジェクト アトゥムも 君島コウも 全部 クソったれだ
お姉ちゃんなんて クソ食らえだ
Damn my sister even!
I won't lose to my perfect superhuman sister!
完璧超人のお姉ちゃんになんて 負けるもんか
何度だって言う
I'll repeat it a hundred times if I have to!
正義は 絶対に勝つんだ
Justice always wins!
Win and save my sister!
勝って うちらが…
お姉ちゃんを助けるんだ
How nice.
立派だ 立派だよ 感動したよ
That's really nice. I'm touched.
But you know,
でもね 君は こう言ってるんだ
that means you're letting this girl die and killing your sister.
この子を見殺しにして 大切な姉を殺しに行くって
See with your own eyes what that means.
それが どういうことなのか
その目で しっかり見るといい
Stop! Stop!
よせ… よせ
Bang!
ボインちゃん
I no like bang!
ボインちゃんじゃねー
Good job, Tarou!
でかしたぞ タロウ
愛理
Airi!
That man?
あの男は？
He's gone.
消えおった
The giant robot of justice...
正義の…巨大ロボット
Hidaka!
日高君
Daitoku?
大徳先輩 どうしたんですか？
Why are you here?
I just couldn't stay still anymore...
え…えーと 何か 居ても立っても いられなくなっちゃって…
I see...
そうですか…
You watched Akiho's speech too, didn't you?
見てたよね？ あき穂ちゃんが しゃべってたの
はい
Yes.
She must've meant this by "giant robot."
あの巨大ロボットって きっと これのことですよね
Um, Hidaka...
あの…日高君…
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
I couldn't apologize properly until today.
私 今日まで 一度も ちゃんと 謝れていなかった
I'm really sorry.
本当に ごめんなさい
Help me if you really mean that.
そう思っているんなら 手伝ってください
Hidaka?
日高君…
If you really want to apologize, apologize without saying sorry.
本当に謝りたいなら ごめんなさいって言葉を使わずに 謝ってみせてください
M-Making his senior apologize and become his slave...
せ…せ…先輩 女子を 謝罪させ 奴隷になることを強要する
せ…性的な意味で
I-In a sexual way!
What eroge is this?
それ 何てエロゲ？
古郡…
Furugoori?
Duhuhu.
Now all the members are here.
これで メンバー勢揃いですね
Hey!
おう やっぱり 揃ってやがったか
You really gathered here.
Grandpa, why are you here?
おじいちゃん どうして ここに…
あのがきが がなってるのを見ちまってな
I saw that brat yelling.
You're planning something here, aren't ya?
何か やらかすつもりなんだろ？
Perhaps...
おそらくは 取りあえず 動くようにしておきましょうか
For now, we should just make it move.
Mass fainting on the SS Anemone
Mysterious mass fainting on an isolated ship
Body found under a cliff on Tanegashima
- possible murder
So it's true?
本当なんだね
What?
何
Your face is pale as a ghost.
顔面蒼白って ああいう顔を いうんだって思った
But Aki and Kai were...
だから それは アキとカイが…
I won't tell anyone nor urge you to give yourself up.
口外するつもりはないし 自首しろとも言わない
Of course I won't tell the police either.
もちろん 警察に駆け込んだりもしない
I just want to help you.
ただ 私は あんたの力になりたい
If I told you back then, you'd have scolded me.
あのとき 私が言ってたら
あなたなら 叱ってくれたかもしれないわね
You're so persistent.
君も しつこい女だ
Don't you understand how pointless it is?
無駄だと まだ分からないのか？
I told you that you'll have to serve me to the end.
君には 最後まで働いてもらうと 言っただろ
Aki! Kai!
アキ… カイ…
You're stubborn.
しかし 君は しぶとい
You became obsessed with me, stopped thinking,
僕に取りつかれると
次第に 思考が停止して 何にも考えない 操り人形になるというのに
and became my mindless puppet.
And yet you still struggle.
最後まで あらがおうとする
Aki! Kai!
アキ… カイ…
The old Tanegashima airport?
旧種子島空港 ？
Great. We can go directly to the hangar then.
よかったよ すぐ ハンガーに行ける
そんな悠長なこと 言ってる場合じゃない
How can you be so relaxed?
It hasn't been used for years!
もう 何年も使ってないんだよ
That's true,
確かにな
but we can't contact the new Tanegashima airport.
しかし 新種子島空港は 連絡がつかないそうだ
ミサ姉たちに制圧されたってこと？
So Misa and her men took over?
見て 種子島
Look, it's Tanegashima!
何か…ずいぶん久しぶりな気がするね
It feels like I've been away for so long...
Yeah.
うん…
こんな小さかったっけ？ 種子島って
Was it always this small?
Huh? I was wondering if it was always this big.
そう？ 俺は こんな大きかったっけって思った
I see...
そっか… そうかも
Yeah, you're right.
Huh?
すごく ちっちゃくて すごく大きいんだよ この島は
It's really small and really big at the same time!
We've got electricity for now, so—
取りあえず 電気は これで確保したので…
What? A plane?
何？ 飛行機？
そ…それにしては近くね？
Isn't it too close?
Oh my god! Look at that!
大変です あれ
It's coming this way.
こっちに向かってるよ
But this airport was closed years ago.
ここ 何年前に封鎖されたと 思ってるんですか？
で…でも…あれは…
But that's...
Hey look!
見ろ
What?
何ぞ？
It's crash landing.
胴体着陸だな
I think it's coming this way.
こっちに向かっているような…
Indeed it is.
間違いなく 向かってきてますね
Shouldn't we, like, run?
逃げた方が よくね？
More like... Run!
というか… 逃げろー
Who's on the plane?
誰が乗ってるんだ？
タ…タ…タイムスリップしてきた戦士的な
Maybe some hero who traveled through time!
Only hot guys accepted!
ただし イケメンに限る
A girl?
女の子…
あ…あ…愛理たん？
Airi?!
President?
部長…
Yashio?
八汐君も
President!
部長
Huh? Why are you all here?
あれ？ みんな…
何で いるの？
Well...
それは…
You all watched my stream, didn't you?
みんな 俺が流した動画 見たんだろ？
Your what?
ミッチー 何かしたの？
Who's that angel?
そ…そ…それより その天使は？
Ah, it's your first time?
初めてだっけ
I'm Yukifune Airi.
行舟 愛理と申します
I'm sorry for tagging along.
すみません 付いてきてしまって
はい？
Huh?
あ…ありのままに あったことを話すぜ
I'm reporting what really seriously happened to me!
Mai waifu, whom I only knew in 2D,
に…二次元だと思っていた俺の嫁が 三次元になって 空から降ってきた
became 3D and fell from the sky!
You might think I just read too many light novels,
ラ…ラノベの読み過ぎだって 言われるかもしれねえが
but that's definitely not it!
断じて そんなもんじゃねえ
Don't mind her.
気にしなくていい
JAXA personnel and the people who couldn't return home because of the solar flares
ＪＡＸＡの職員と 太陽嵐の報道に 帰宅できなくなった人たちは
took shelter here and the sports hall in the park.
この学校と運動公園の体育館に 避難しています
So the armed troops failed to take over the airport and Frau Bow's place,
じゃあ 武装集団は 空港と フラウ坊襲撃には 失敗して
but they're still in control of JAXA?
ＪＡＸＡだけを 占拠してるってこと？
Yes.
そうなります
The police?
警察は？
They're still in panic because of the fake solar flare news.
まだ 太陽嵐が到達したという偽情報にパニック状態です
まさに 君島コウの狙いどおりか
It's all according to Kimijima Kou's plans.
お前ら ドクが学校に着いたってよ
Doc's arrived at the school.
Really?
本当？
I'll take Airi to the nurse's office.
俺は 愛理さん 保健室に送っていくから 先行ってる
I'm going ahead.
Are you feeling okay?
体は平気？
Yes. Thank you for everything.
はい
色々 ありがとうございました
Year 3             Class 2
GunPro-1 Plans
This is GunPro-1?
これが ガンつく１？
Yeah. For now, let's change every motor to a monopole motor to improve its mobility.
取りあえず モーターを 全部 モノポールモーターに替え 機動性をアップする
In addition to that, I think we should attach a pile bunker to its arm.
それに加え 手には パイルバンカーを装着しようと思います
Pile... Where would we get that?
パイル… そんなもの あるの？
I made one before for fun.
俺が趣味で造ったのがな
With that mischievious face on.
そして この どや顔である
But do we have time to do all that?
でも そんなに改造してる 時間あるの？
It's not about being able to do it. We've got no choice!
できる できねえじゃねえ やるしかねえ
That's what I call rock!
それがロックだ
Let's consider our situation.
では 状況を整理しておきましょうか
The armed troops took control of the space center.
武装集団は 宇宙センターを占拠
目的は ブラックホール爆弾をロケットで 打ち上げることにあります
Their goal is to launch the black hole bomb with a rocket.
They can only launch it once the weather gets better.
打ち上げは 天候回復後の いずれかの時間
それまでに ガンつく１を改造し
We must modify the GunPro-1 until then,
敵の戦力であるＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩを突破し これを阻止するしかありません
break through the enemy's SUMERAGI, and prevent the launch.
If they can launch the rocket, 5 billion people will die.
ロケットが打ち上がれば ５０億の命が失われる
No way!
そんな… 責任 重大過ぎるよ
That's such a huge responsibility!
でも やるしかないよ そのために戻ってきたんだし
But we've got no choice.
That's why we came back.
Akiho...
あき穂ちゃん…
そ…そういえば ＪＡＸＡを占拠しているのって 部長の姉…
But isn't the leader of the armed troops your sister?
And the hostage is your father...
人質は お父さんなんだよね
Yeah.
みんなは そのことは気にしないで
But don't worry about that.
大切なのは 正義のロボットは きっと勝つ
The robot of justice will win for sure.
そのために みんなの力を合わせること
We need to work together for that.
Very well.
分かりました
じゃあ 昴とドクは みんなに指示を出して ガンつく１の改造を急いで
Subaru and Doc will give directions to complete the GunPro-1 mods as soon as possible.
分かりました
Okay.
Jun, you help Subaru.
ジュンは 昴のサポート
オ…オス
Roger!
Frau Bow, you look at the program Kai got from Sawada.
フラウ坊は さっき カイの所に来た澤田って人からのプログラムを 見て
Sawada?
澤田？
The connection is still unstable, so the download isn't going well though.
ネットが まだ不安定だからなかなか ダウンロードできないんだけど
どうやら ＳＵＭＥＲＡＧＩに対抗する プログラムみたいなんだ
It seems to be a program to counter SUMERAGI.
Subject:
From: Sawada
Don't use Iru-O. Install the DG297 we developed.
『居ル夫 』は使えない
開発させていた ＤＧ２９７を インストールしろ
何？ この 上から目線なメール
Why is he ordering us around like that?
だが それがいい
But that turns me on.
じゃあ そっち送るから 後は 何とかして
I'll send it over then. The rest is on you.
I've gotta head out for a bit.
俺は ちょっと 出てくるから
Where are you going, Kai?
カイ どっか行くの？
This is an EM wave projector device.
電磁波照射装置 相手に幻を見せることができる
It can make people see things.
We could use this as a weapon, couldn't we?
使えれば 武器になるだろ？
元は 君島コウが作ったものだから
It was made by Kimijima Kou, so we might find something out if we analyze it.
調べれば 何か分かると思うんだ
Kai...
カイ…
And there's another mischievious face.
そして この男も どや顔である
All of you!
あなたたち
いったい 何をやっているんです？
What do you think you are doing?
I remember telling you that the Robotics Club was disbanded.
ロボ部は廃部と言ったはずですよ
Principal?
教頭先生…
But...
そんな…
Come on, we don't—
あのね 今は そんなこと…
I am not interested in your excuses.
言い訳は聞きません
If you insist, sign these.
どうしても やるというなら ここにサインしなさい
Give us a break! The school's got—
勘弁してよ もう 学校なんて言って…
Kai, these are membership forms...
カイ… これ 入部届
Member
Application
I am telling you to reform the Robotics Club before you begin.
作業に入る前に ロボ部を再び設立しなさいと 言っているんです
Otherwise, you could no longer make the school take responsibility if something happened.
でないと 何かあったとき 学校の責任ですと 言えなくなってしまいます
Principal...
先生…
Mitchie?
ミッチー
Principal, will this do?
教頭 こんなもんで いいですか？
What's this? So much!
何これ？ すごい量
It still does not compare to the help all the students offered you.
少ないくらいです
あなたたちの手伝いを 買って出た生徒の分にしては
Huh?
嘘…
No way!
Hey, Yashio!
八汐 手伝いに来たー
We're here to help!
Guys...
みんな…
Sorry for the wait!
待たせたな
ＪＡＸＡの技術者 連れてきました
I brought along some engineers from JAXA!
すげぇ
すご～い
Father?
父さん…
アキちゃんの言ったとおりだね
It's just as you said, Aki.
This island's really small and really big at the same time.
この島は すごく ちっちゃくて すごく おっきい
Misaki...
みさ希…
Run now!
早く行って… 早く
Hurry!
But you...
しかし お前は…
駄目なの…私の中に こいつがいるかぎり 私は…
I can't! Not while he's in my head!
I....
早く
Hurry!
I told you before, didn't I?
前に教えたはずだよ
If you resist too much, your mind will deteriorate.
あまり抵抗し過ぎると 自我が崩壊すると
構わないわ きっと アキとカイが…
I don't care. Aki and Kai will...
Sister Centipede...
ゲジ姉…
はい
Yes?
I release you.
あなたを解放するわ
Command unknown.
理解できません
あの２人の所へ
Go to those two...
のっちよ…ゲジ姉
Goodbye... Sister Centipede.
Trans
Transfer
Transfer com
Transfer complete
それはふとした瞬間に
All those unexpected moments
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
As you mumble on and on
それがいつしか価値観さえも
Will overcome even my standards
超えてしまうんだよ
In the end
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
All those goodbyes we said
明日への階段をのぼる
As we climb the stairway to the future
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Light will always hold this planet together
奇跡のように命が集まって
Lives gather as if by some miracle
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
Showing the outline of a lively scene
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
取り上げる思いが
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
描いた空
柔らかな風が吹き
The wind blows gently stroking
新しい道となり
Turning into a new path
いつだってその道は
A path that will always
この場所に繋がってる
Lead us to this place
Tune in next week too!